<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
<h2>Journal papers</h2>
Uncertainty quantification take a lot of time, but can be sped up significantly. Read about our method in the paper below, and see the 'coral' tool for an Open Source Python implementation. 
<div class='reference'>
Berends, K.D., Warmink, J.J., Hulscher, S.J.M.H., 2018, Efficient uncertainty quantification for impact analysis of human interventions in rivers, Environmental Modelling &amp; Software 107, 50-58. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envsoft.2018.05.021 ">doi: 10.1016/j.envsoft.2018.05.021 	</a>
</div>
<br/>
From previous studies we know that uncertainty in roughness causes large uncertainty in expected water levels during floods. But how does this translate to predictions of river engineering? In the paper below, we explore this for the River Waal. 
<br/>
<div class='reference'>
<img style="width: 14px;" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/7/77/Open_Access_logo_PLoS_transparent.svg"></img>
Berends, K. D., Straatsma, M. W., Warmink, J. J., and Hulscher, S. J. M. H.: Uncertainty quantification of flood mitigation predictions and implications for decision making, Nat. Hazards Earth Syst. Sci. Discuss., <a href="https://www.nat-hazards-earth-syst-sci-discuss.net/nhess-2018-325">https://doi.org/10.5194/nhess-2018-325 </a>, in review, 2018. </div>

<h2>  Tools </h2>
<a href="https://github.com/kdberends/coral"><img style='width: 90%' type="image/svg+xml" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kdberends/coral/master/coralfig.svg?sanitize=true"></img></a>
Coral is a Python package that can be used for efficient uncertainty estimation, in dealing with computationally demanding models. Click on the link above to go directly to the source code. 

<h2> Other projects </h2>
<a href="https://kbase.ncr-web.org/rivercare"><img style='width: 90%' type="image/svg+xml" src="img/rivercarelogo_black.svg"></img></a>

My research is not done in a vacuum. In fact, my project is one of 21 in the RiverCare research project, running from 2015-2019!

</xml>